Ivan Grishaev

An IT engineer focused exclusively on Clojure for the last 6 years. With long Python/Delphi/PHP experience in the past.

Tags: Clojure(Script), Postgres, Datomic, Kafka, Python. Emacs, LaTeX.

Russia, Voronezh, UTC +3.

Links:

- ivan@grishaev.me
- github.com/igrishaev
- linkedin.com/in/igrishaev

Summary

- 6 years of Clojure in production (Aleph/manifold stack, core.async, Component/Integrant);
- experience with different data sources: PG, Datomic, Kafka, Cassandra, etc.
- some experience with frontend: re-frame, React;
- mobile development: Re-Natal with some bits of Obj-C/Swift;
- knowledge of Python/Django;
- good with Emacs and LaTeX.

Clojure contribution

I maintain about ten Clojure libraries hosted on Github. One of them is Etaoin which is widely used (700 stars, spotted in many companies).

I wrote a short book in English about Java interop. Get in on Leanpub.

I wrote a full printed book in Russian called "Clojure in Production". The book covers web development, Clojure.spec, exception handling, systems, testing and other subjects. It is partially translated to English in my blog.

Experience

Dec 2018 — Feb 2022: Senior Clojure developer @

Exoscale (Switzerland)

At Exoscale, I mostly worked on various network orchestrators. We had plenty of data sources like Mysql, Cassandra, Kafka which required precise control. I used Aleph & Manifold stack for my apps. I maintained some legacy apps driven with Core.async.

Exoscale has plenty of internal stuff which I contributed to. One of them is a web framework built on top of Open-API spec and data schemas.

I made an app to upload vast files (+100Gb) to our infrastructure.

I integrated the web SSH terminal to the admin page (noVNC, JavaScript, Clojure on backend).

I made a draft of the official CLI utility for Exoscale API. That was a Clojure project compiled with GraalVM/native-image. The file size was 25Mb, and the performance was faster than Golang's.

During the last year at Exoscale, I worked on DBaaS: a massive feature that integrates a third-party database provider into the Exoscale infrastructure. That involved HTTP API, data processing, reconciliation, billing processing and more.

Jan 2018 — Dec 2018: Senior Clojure developer @ Health Samurai (Russia)

Health Samurai is a startup focused on medical data. They develop FHIR-compatible software, and I was working on several internal services. One of them named US NPI is open source and may be found on GitHub. This service fetches the official US NPI registry and fills the database. It also provides flexible REST API, search capabilities and Swagger UI.

I spent four months working on a mobile app for iOS. The app was driven by Re-Natal and ClojureScript. We managed to pass Apple's review and had the app released in App Store.

2016 — Dec 2017: Clojure developer @ Flyerbee (Switzerland)

Flyerbee is a web app that automates outdooring advertisements. I worked on both server and UI parts using a modified version of the Luminus stack. That included Clojure, Ring, JDBC/PostgreSQL, and Re-frame.

2015 — 2016: Python developer @ SwiftServe (UK)

SwiftServe is a worldwide CDN network that competes with AWS CloudFront. I developed three internal services written in Python and Django and set up micro-service architecture in AWS cloud. I integrated a modern unit-test framework into our pipeline and added a new documentation system.

2013 — 2015: Python developer @ Dataart

DataArt is a vast outsourcing company. The main project I've been working on was a worldwide online game with 70M players. I developed several internal services, set up message queues and wrote lots of unit tests.

2008 — 2013: Various contracting jobs

I've been working on various projects including Python, Delphi, and PHP. My clients were mostly individuals and small companies. I developed desktop apps, websites and simple Android applications.

Education

Bachelor's Degree at Applied Informatics in Economics, Chita University of Economics, 2003 – 2008

Other

I am a father of three. Enjoy winter activities. Run my blog in both English and Russian. Educate a couple of students.